# **AHMAD RAZA**

# Brooklyn, NY 11230

linkedin.com/in/Razatastic • github.com/Razatastic • me@razatastic.com • 347-828-6637

## **SUMMARY**

Collaborative, creative computer science student with experience in Object-Oriented Programming, web development and Linux administration. Strong foundation in programming logic, problem solving and cross-platform coding. Winner of the Codecademy prize at the 2018 CUNY Hackathon.

#### **EDUCATION**

# B.S., Computer Science, Brooklyn College/CUNY

Graduation expected - May 2019

- **GPA:** 3.8
- Relevant Coursework: Advance C++, Analysis of Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Discrete Structures, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Design and Implementation

### **PROJECTS**

## CommuniTii, New York, NY

April 2018 - Present

- Developed an app for non-profits that encourages people to socialize in-person and give back to the community through the use of gamification. (React Native Express, Firebase, Adobe XD)
- Awarded Codecademy Prize at the 2018 CUNY Hackathon.
- Accepted into the CUNY Startup Accelerator program.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# STAPLES, INC., Brooklyn, NY

July 2015 – November 2015

EasyTech Sales Associate (Full-time)

- Achieved weekly sales goals of \$2,500 by engaging 30 customers daily by asking open-ended questions and providing recommendations based on interests and needs.
- Built relationships with Certified Tech Associates to create synergy across all technology departments.
- Resolved technical and non-technical customer concerns over the phone and in-person.
- Participated in bi-monthly team meetings to learn about new technologies, products and services.

## **NEW YORK CITY DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION, Brooklyn, NY**

September 2011 – November 2014

Student Aide (Full-time & Part-time)

- Collaborated with administration and aided in solving technical problems that arose day-to-day.
- Handled complex computer troubleshooting issues for 5,000+ students and 200 faculty members weekly.
- Regulated 3,000+ workstations by setting up networks and reimaging/ghosting entire classrooms to maintain a fully working environment.
- Managed and updated spreadsheet of inventory consisting of hardware components weekly.
- Provided onsite training and assistance to roughly 2-3 new employees every term.

## **LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES**

# NEW YORK UNIVERSITY, TANDON SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, Brooklyn, NY

February 2016

Volunteer

 Participated in the annual NYU Hackathon assisting participants create a working development environment.

#### **SKILLS AND INTERESTS**

**Technical:** Java, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Native, Firebase, Bootstrap, SASS, Git/SVN, Electron, Expo, Bash scripting, Adobe XD, Figma, Google Cloud Platform, Parallels, VMWare, VirtualBox, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code and Linux/Unix.

**Language:** Fluent Urdu and Conversational French. **Interests:** Technology, Entrepreneurship, and Traveling.